Haseeb Ullah Khan

Senior Front-end Software Engineer

Portfolio

I started with Web Development in 2018 and worked on small to medium applications. I have completed 16 years of formal education. My major was Computer Science and Software Engineering. I joined Meveto as a front-end software engineer in Sept 2020. A few months later, I was promoted to Senior Front-end Software Engineer. I have significant experience with every aspect of web and mobile development. I excel at converting Figma designs to code and collaborating with back-end developers. I am detail-oriented, a problem-solver, and a team player.

Skills

HTML/CSS	React Redux	MUI	Aws
JavaScript	React Native	Git	
TypeScript	Next.js	GitHub	
React Js	Tailwind CSS	Vercel	

Experience

Senior Front-end Software Engineer

Meveto Inc

Sep 2021 to Present - 1 yr 6 mos

- ▶ I built a **Lead Tracking Portal** for the Meveto marketing team. The tool was used internally as a bespoke CRM.
- ▶ I built the entire **Admin Panel** for the Meveto team, both, Frontend and Backend. We initially used Electron for the desktop app but then I converted it to a web-based app using React.
- ▶ I participated in implementing a completely new design for the Meveto mobile apps. We used **React Native with TypeScript**.
- ▶ I refactored majority of the Meveto's user dashboard (Frontend). The dashboard is built with React + Redux.
- I converted 70% of the codebase to use Redux Toolkit and RTK **Query** instead of error-prone vanilla Redux implementation.
- ▶ I participated in **code reviews and training** of new colleagues.

Front-end Software Engineer Meveto Inc

Sep 2020 to Sep 2021 - 1 yr

- I built the Meveto documentation portal. The portal documented Meveto APIs, SDKs, and WordPress plugins for developers.
- ▶ I helped transition from bootstrap to tailwind CSS at the front end.
- ▶ I took part in the majority of the **initial UI pages** that were developed at that time.

Experience

Founder Depart

Jul 2020 to Jul 2021 - 1 yr

I built Depart for the university where I did my Bachelor's degree. It is a bespoke web and mobile app to automate most of the work related to student and faculty transport. The app can be used by travelers (students, faculty, etc.) and university administration. Travelers can use it to request transport facilities for an available route and to communicate with transport staff for any query. Admins can use it for many tasks. Several tasks worth mentioning are:

- > Store and process travelers', drivers', and conductors' data.
- Manage vehicle information like scheduling routes and departure and arrival times.
- Print travel passes (cards) for travelers.
- Manage vehicle routes and meter readings to calculate average fuel consumption.
- ➤ Send real-time notifications for route changes, vehicle changes, vehicle issues, and traffic conditions.

Education

BSC (Hons) Software Engineering Sep 2017 - Jul 2021

National University of Modern Languages (NUML)

I have completed 16 years of formal education. My major was Computer Science and Software Engineering.